# SAMUEL OJO

#### • FRONT-FND DEVELOPER •

samuelojo.dev@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/greatsamuelojo • http://github.com/greatsamist

#### **PROFILE**

A dedicated JavaScript developer specializing in front end development, with a particular focus on utilizing the React library to build interactive user interfaces. With a strong passion for crafting exceptional user experiences, I actively focus on areas such as Design Systems, Web Accessibility, and Serverless Technologies including AWS and Google Cloud. I strive to deliver highly engaging and accessible applications that meet the needs of both users and businesses.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Front-end Developer | NetOne Talent • Alpharetta, GA • Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

Built and maintained a project that provides immediate on-demand access to comprehensively vetted contracting talent. My primary focus was building a new UI and improving the site speed using React and SCSS. Additionally, I implemented a real-time messaging functionality, allowing clients to promptly address any time logging concerns with their hired talents. Currently, this project has out-performs traditional recruitment providers in delivery speed, quality of contractors, and efficiency, according to Fortune 500 clients.

#### Front-end Developer | Web3Bridge • Lagos, NG • Nov 2020 - Sep 2022

By implementing automated testing with React Testing Library, I ensured code quality, reduced bugs, and facilitated seamless integration with CI/CD pipelines. Leveraging Git version control, I collaborated smoothly with designers and product managers, improving code integration and project workflows. Additionally, I played a major role in building the company's DAO and NFT smart contract using Solidity and integrated the smart contract with React using ether.js, This has raised over \$100k value in NFT's minted.

#### Front-end Developer | Felfo Digital • Lagos, NG • Dec 2019 - Sept 2020

By utilizing the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js, I empowered small and medium enterprises (SMEs) to take advantage of the digital space. With a dedicated focus on React, I created immersive and cutting-edge user interfaces that captivate audiences and drive impactful interactions. As a result, our services led to a remarkable 75% increase in clients' visibility and conversions, along with a substantial 40% growth in their revenue.

### TECH STACK

JavaScript	React	HTML5/CSS3	Bootstrap	Graphql
TypeScript	Nextjs	SASS/LESS	REST APIs	Jest/Mocha/Chai
Solidity	Node.js	Material Design	MongoDb	Git (Gitlab, Github)

# **EDUCATION**

## Ladoke Akintola University of technology, NG - Nov 2019

Bachelor of Technology in Physics